Daniel Parkson Tano

TKC, TKC, Yaounde, Centre • 237674128573 • tanoparksonsilencer@gmail.com • linkedin.com/in/daniel-parkson-tano • https://twitter.com/ParksonDaniel • https://www.parksontano.com/

Full Stack Developer

5+ years of experience developing, testing, and deploying web-based applications, resulting in increased user performance, cost savings, team productivity, and client satisfaction. Lead Full Stack Developer for Upscale Innovation, developed and deployed a web-based HR management application in 1 month, reducing web development time by 40%.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Upscale innovation • Romote • Full-time • 03/2023 - Present **Lead Full Stack developer**

- Developed, tested, and deployed a web-based application for a company's HR management in 1 month, increasing user HR performance by 90%. And database designs for MySQL
- Reduced web development time by 40% in 3 months, resulting in \$20k annual cost savings.
- Created and implemented an efficient project management system that improved team productivity by 30%, resulting in quicker project delivery times and increased client satisfaction
- Led a team of developers to successfully design and implement a complex web application using Git for version control and AWS for hosting.

Tantorial • Yaounde • 07/2021 - Present

Full-stack Developer

- Led a team of developers to successfully design and implement a complex web application using Git for version control and AWS for hosting.
- Developed efficient and scalable full-stack solutions for various projects, resulting in high level of satisfaction and increased repeat business. Built and maintain MySQL database
- Implemented agile methodologies and best practices, resulting in a 30% increase in efficiency and productivity and a 25% reduction in overhead costs in 2 months

Imobbis • Yaounde • Part-time • 06/2021 - 05/2022

Django Back End Developer

- Developed, implemented, and maintained complex REST APIs using Django Rest Framework for a real estate-oriented social network in Cameroon. Migrated from PHP to Django in 2 months
- Implemented Git version control to facilitate efficient teamwork with colleagues. Deployed the application on AWS infrastructure to ensure maximum availability and scalability
- Contributed to the development of key features such as user authentication, property listing, and messaging functionality. Increasing feature delivery by 45%

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science

higher teacher training college, university of maroua

Google Data Analytics Certificate

SKILLS

Software Development, Django REST Framework, React.js, Python (Programming Language), JavaScript, RESTful WebServices, Analysis, JS Frameworks